hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist now continuing with our topic
on test automation obstacles moving on
to our next topic is confusing dates so
this is the obstacle which uh consists
of different date formats and different
calculations which we need to do so
let's see at this particular problem
right so we need to generate a new date
in the US format by pressing the
calendar button so this is the button
when you press on it a specific date is
generated in a specific format now we
need to use the tosar based functions to
calculate first of the second following
month of the generated date okay so uh
we need to calculate 2 months uh forward
and and it has to be the first of that
particular following month right uh and
then the new date has to be entered in
this particular text box uh and that has
to be in the iso format there's an
example here so if the date is this then
uh the result date should be this okay
and once you do that you need to click
on this done button now for example if
our generated date is this then our
resultant date should be
okay so we have to enter the year first
and then we need to calculate two months
in advance okay so that would be 10 and
then
okay and you will see that the obstacle
is completed now so this is what we need
to automate using tosa so let's see how
we can do this in
tosa Okay so coming back to our tosa
workspace uh and going to our obstacles
modules folder we will scan the
application and here we need to add
basically four controls okay so we need
to add the buttons and then the two text
boxes so one is the generated date and
one is the solution
date okay so these are all the four
controls which we require and then I'm
going to rename this module
here and then I'm going to save and
close this okay and now coming back to
our obstacle test cases folder we are
going to add new test case
here and then uh we are going to add the
particular module to this particular
test case Okay uh now before we move
ahead and uh modify our test steps we
need to add some additional
configuration parameters to our module
attributes and this is because of the
specific date formats right so these two
are the module attributes or basically
the date controls so for this we need to
change the properties okay so in the
property section we need to right click
and there we will be finding a
configuration parameter option so we'll
click on that and here uh we need to
provide the target format okay so this
is the configuration parameter name okay
uh it is a system defined parameters so
the name should be exactly defined like
this okay okay and then the value uh
would be uh this particular format so
which is the month then the date and
then the year okay and uh we need to do
the same for the solution date field as
well so we will add a configuration
parameter and we will call it Target
date
format and we will enter the same value
here so this is the format and then we
will go back to our test case now and we
will modify the test step values here so
first we need to click on the button to
generate the date so we will perform the
click operation then once the date is
generated uh we have to save it into a
buffer okay so that we will do um I will
Prov provide a name here called
generated
date now when this date is generated we
also need to change the data type
because it cannot be string anymore okay
it has to be a date data type okay so we
need to change the data type to date
here and then uh we need to perform some
calculations here okay so we need to use
a data expression which is called month
first and what does it do it Returns the
first day of the current month as a
complete date
okay so inside this uh we are going to
provide the base date which is nothing
but our buffer so we will use that
here okay and after this we need to
perform some offset calculations because
we need to calculate 2 months uh after
the generated date right so we will do
plus two months
here right
and then uh we need to do it in a
specific format right so we will put the
format here uh and that will be
year then month and then
date
okay okay so uh I have changed that to
month first somehow it became
month uh but this is the expression
which will use use and once that is done
once the calculation is done we need to
click on the done button okay so again a
click operation so these are all the
operations which we need to perform in
our test steps and once that is done uh
we can mark this as completed and now
let's go ahead and run this in
scratchbook okay so as you can see uh it
generated the date and then it performed
all the calculations then it entered it
into the text box and then it clicked on
the done button which completes all the
requirements for this particular
obstacle okay so this is how you can
perform different uh date calculations
uh it could be on a base date it could
be on a default date or it could be some
generated date right so there could be
several scenarios in your application
where you can apply this particular
knowledge uh you can use different data
Expressions which are available in tosa
to perform different types of date
calculations that's all for this
particular video if you have any
questions then please leave it in the
comments if you like this video then
please subscribe to our Channel thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next
video